wildhorsepm.com 2018-09-22

# Privacy Policy - Wild Horse Performance Marketing

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://wildhorsepm.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

## Who we share your data with

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

## Additional information

**SECTION 1 – WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION?**

WHEN YOU PURCHASE SOMETHING FROM OUR STORE, AS PART OF THE BUYING AND SELLING PROCESS, WE COLLECT THE PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU GIVE US SUCH AS YOUR NAME, ADDRESS AND EMAIL ADDRESS.

WHEN YOU BROWSE OUR STORE, WE ALSO AUTOMATICALLY RECEIVE YOUR COMPUTER’S INTERNET PROTOCOL (IP) ADDRESS IN ORDER TO PROVIDE US WITH INFORMATION THAT HELPS US LEARN ABOUT YOUR BROWSER AND OPERATING SYSTEM.

EMAIL MARKETING (IF APPLICABLE): WITH YOUR PERMISSION, WE MAY SEND YOU EMAILS ABOUT OUR STORE, NEW PRODUCTS AND OTHER UPDATES.

**SECTION 2 – CONSENT**

HOW DO YOU GET MY CONSENT?

WHEN YOU PROVIDE US WITH PERSONAL INFORMATION TO COMPLETE A TRANSACTION, VERIFY YOUR CREDIT CARD, PLACE AN ORDER, ARRANGE FOR A DELIVERY OR RETURN A PURCHASE, WE IMPLY THAT YOU CONSENT TO OUR COLLECTING IT AND USING IT FOR THAT SPECIFIC REASON ONLY.

IF WE ASK FOR YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR A SECONDARY REASON, LIKE MARKETING, WE WILL EITHER ASK YOU DIRECTLY FOR YOUR EXPRESSED CONSENT, OR PROVIDE YOU WITH AN OPPORTUNITY TO SAY NO.

**HOW DO I WITHDRAW MY CONSENT?**

IF AFTER YOU OPT-IN, YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND, YOU MAY WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT FOR US TO CONTACT YOU, FOR THE CONTINUED COLLECTION, USE OR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION, AT ANY TIME, BY CONTACTING US BY USING OUR CONTACT FORM.

**SECTION 3 – DISCLOSURE**

WE MAY DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IF WE ARE REQUIRED BY LAW TO DO SO OR IF YOU VIOLATE OUR TERMS OF SERVICE.

**SECTION 4 – THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

IN GENERAL, THE THIRD-PARTY PROVIDERS USED BY US WILL ONLY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION TO THE EXTENT NECESSARY TO ALLOW THEM TO PERFORM THE SERVICES THEY PROVIDE TO US.

HOWEVER, CERTAIN THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS, SUCH AS PAYMENT GATEWAYS AND OTHER PAYMENT TRANSACTION PROCESSORS, HAVE THEIR OWN PRIVACY POLICIES IN RESPECT TO THE INFORMATION WE ARE REQUIRED TO PROVIDE TO THEM FOR YOUR PURCHASE-RELATED TRANSACTIONS.

FOR THESE PROVIDERS, WE RECOMMEND THAT YOU READ THEIR PRIVACY POLICIES SO YOU CAN UNDERSTAND THE MANNER IN WHICH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WILL BE HANDLED BY THESE PROVIDERS.

IN PARTICULAR, REMEMBER THAT CERTAIN PROVIDERS MAY BE LOCATED IN OR HAVE FACILITIES THAT ARE LOCATED A DIFFERENT JURISDICTION THAN EITHER YOU OR US. SO IF YOU ELECT TO PROCEED WITH A TRANSACTION THAT INVOLVES THE SERVICES OF A THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDER, THEN YOUR INFORMATION MAY BECOME SUBJECT TO THE LAWS OF THE JURISDICTION(S) IN WHICH THAT SERVICE PROVIDER OR ITS FACILITIES ARE LOCATED.

AS AN EXAMPLE, IF YOU ARE LOCATED IN CANADA AND YOUR TRANSACTION IS PROCESSED BY A PAYMENT GATEWAY LOCATED IN THE UNITED STATES, THEN YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION USED IN COMPLETING THAT TRANSACTION MAY BE SUBJECT TO DISCLOSURE UNDER UNITED STATES LEGISLATION, INCLUDING THE PATRIOT ACT.

ONCE YOU LEAVE OUR STORE’S WEBSITE OR ARE REDIRECTED TO A THIRD-PARTY WEBSITE OR APPLICATION, YOU ARE NO LONGER GOVERNED BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR OUR WEBSITE’S TERMS OF SERVICE.

WHEN YOU CLICK ON LINKS ON OUR STORE, THEY MAY DIRECT YOU AWAY FROM OUR SITE. WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PRIVACY PRACTICES OF OTHER SITES AND ENCOURAGE YOU TO READ THEIR PRIVACY STATEMENTS.

**SECTION 5 – SECURITY**

TO PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, WE TAKE REASONABLE PRECAUTIONS AND FOLLOW INDUSTRY BEST PRACTICES TO MAKE SURE IT IS NOT INAPPROPRIATELY LOST, MISUSED, ACCESSED, DISCLOSED, ALTERED OR DESTROYED.

IF YOU PROVIDE US WITH YOUR CREDIT CARD INFORMATION, THE INFORMATION IS ENCRYPTED USING SECURE SOCKET LAYER TECHNOLOGY (SSL) AND STORED WITH A AES-256 ENCRYPTION. ALTHOUGH NO METHOD OF TRANSMISSION OVER THE INTERNET OR ELECTRONIC STORAGE IS 100% SECURE, WE FOLLOW ALL PCI-DSS REQUIREMENTS AND IMPLEMENT ADDITIONAL GENERALLY ACCEPTED INDUSTRY STANDARDS.

**COLLECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING MAY COLLECT PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION, WHEN YOU SIGN UP ON OUR MEMBERSHIP SITE AS A MEMBER ON [HTTPS://WILDHORSEPM.COM](http://wildhorsepm.com/) WE COLLECT INFORMATION SUCH AS YOUR:

  1. NAME
  2. ADDRESS
  3. E-MAIL ADDRESS
  4. PHONE NUMBER

[HTT](https://targetinsider.com/)[PS://WILDHORSEPM.COM ](http://wildhorsepm.com/)MAY ALSO COLLECT ANONYMOUS DEMOGRAPHIC INFORMATION, WHICH IS NOT UNIQUE TO YOU.

WE MAY GATHER ADDITIONAL PERSONAL OR NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION IN THE FUTURE.

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING ENCOURAGES YOU TO REVIEW THE PRIVACY STATEMENTS OF WEBSITES YOU CHOOSE TO LINK TO FROM WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING SO THAT YOU CAN UNDERSTAND HOW THOSE WEBSITES COLLECT, USE AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION.  WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PRIVACY STATEMENTS OR OTHER CONTENT ON WEBSITES OUTSIDE OF THE WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING WEBSITE.

**EMAIL POLICIES**

WE ARE COMMITTED TO KEEPING YOUR E-MAIL ADDRESS CONFIDENTIAL. WE DO NOT SELL, RENT, OR LEASE OUR SUBSCRIPTION LISTS TO THIRD PARTIES, AND WE WILL NOT PROVIDE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO ANY THIRD PARTY INDIVIDUAL, GOVERNMENT AGENCY, OR COMPANY AT ANY TIME UNLESS STRICTLY COMPELLED TO DO SO BY LAW.

WE WILL USE YOUR E-MAIL ADDRESS SOLELY TO PROVIDE TIMELY INFORMATION ABOUT.

WE WILL MAINTAIN THE INFORMATION YOU SEND VIA E-MAIL IN ACCORDANCE WITH APPLICABLE FEDERAL LAW.

**WE DO NOT SELL, RENT OR LEASE ITS CUSTOMER LISTS TO THIRD PARTIES.**

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING MAY, FROM TIME TO TIME, CONTACT YOU ON BEHALF OF EXTERNAL BUSINESS PARTNERS ABOUT A PARTICULAR OFFERING THAT MAY BE OF INTEREST TO YOU. IN THOSE CASES, YOUR UNIQUE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION (E-MAIL, NAME, ADDRESS, TELEPHONE NUMBER) IS TRANSFERRED TO THE THIRD PARTY. WE MAY SHARE DATA WITH TRUSTED PARTNERS TO HELP PERFORM STATISTICAL ANALYSIS, SEND YOU EMAIL OR POSTAL MAIL, PROVIDE CUSTOMER SUPPORT, OR ARRANGE FOR DELIVERIES. ALL SUCH THIRD PARTIES ARE PROHIBITED FROM USING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION EXCEPT TO PROVIDE THESE SERVICES TO WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING, AND THEY ARE REQUIRED TO MAINTAIN THE CONFIDENTIALITY OF YOUR INFORMATION.

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING WILL DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, WITHOUT NOTICE, ONLY IF REQUIRED TO DO SO BY LAW OR IN THE GOOD FAITH BELIEF THAT SUCH ACTION IS NECESSARY TO: (A) CONFORM TO THE EDICTS OF THE LAW OR COMPLY WITH LEGAL PROCESS SERVED ON WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING OR THE SITE; (B) PROTECT AND DEFEND THE RIGHTS OR PROPERTY OF WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING; AND, (C) ACT UNDER EXIGENT CIRCUMSTANCES TO PROTECT THE PERSONAL SAFETY OF USERS OF WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING, OR THE PUBLIC.

**CAN-SPAM COMPLIANCE**

IN COMPLIANCE WITH THE CAN-SPAM ACT, ALL E-MAIL SENT FROM OUR ORGANIZATION WILL CLEARLY STATE WHO THE E-MAIL IS FROM AND PROVIDE CLEAR INFORMATION ON HOW TO CONTACT THE SENDER. IN ADDITION, ALL E-MAIL MESSAGES WILL ALSO CONTAIN CONCISE INFORMATION ON HOW TO REMOVE YOURSELF FROM OUR MAILING LIST SO THAT YOU RECEIVE NO FURTHER E-MAIL COMMUNICATION FROM US.

**DATA UNDER EU GDPR COMPLIANCE**

HERE AT WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING, WE RESPECT AND VALUE THE RIGHT TO PRIVACY. WE ARE ALSO CONSUMERS AND KNOW THAT IT IS OUR RESPONSIBILITY TO BUILD A COMPANY THAT PROTECTS CONSUMER PRIVACY. ALL OF OUR SERVICES ARE DESIGNED TO PROTECT PRIVACY AND PERSONAL DATA OF CONSUMERS.

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING IS CONSIDERED A “DATA PROCESSOR” UNDER THE GUIDELINES OF THE GDPR. OUR CUSTOMERS ARE PRIMARILY CONSIDERED TO BE “DATA CONTROLLERS”, AND ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR MEETING ADDITIONAL PRIVACY OR CONSENT GATHERING REQUIREMENTS FOR THEIR INDIVIDUAL USE CASE.

**INFORMATION WE PROCESS BECAUSE WE HAVE A CONTRACTUAL OBLIGATION WITH YOU**

WHEN YOU USE WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO OUR TERMS AND CONDITIONS, A CONTRACT IS FORMED BETWEEN YOU AND US.

IN ORDER TO CARRY OUT OUR OBLIGATIONS UNDER THAT CONTRACT WE MUST PROCESS THE INFORMATION YOU GIVE US. SOME OF THIS INFORMATION MAY BE PERSONAL INFORMATION.

WE MAY USE IT IN ORDER TO:

  1. VERIFY YOUR IDENTITY FOR SECURITY PURPOSES
  2. SELL PRODUCTS TO YOU
  3. PROVIDE YOU WITH OUR SERVICES
  4. PROVIDE YOU WITH SUGGESTIONS AND ADVICE ON SERVICES AND HOW TO OBTAIN THE MOST FROM USING OUR WEBSITE

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING PROCESSES THIS INFORMATION ON THE BASIS THERE IS A CONTRACT BETWEEN US, OR THAT YOU HAVE REQUESTED WE USE THE INFORMATION BEFORE WE ENTER INTO A LEGAL CONTRACT.

ADDITIONALLY, WE MAY AGGREGATE THIS INFORMATION IN A GENERAL WAY AND USE IT TO PROVIDE CLASS INFORMATION, FOR EXAMPLE TO MONITOR OUR PERFORMANCE WITH RESPECT TO A PARTICULAR SERVICE WE PROVIDE. IF WE USE IT FOR THIS PURPOSE, YOU AS AN INDIVIDUAL WILL NOT BE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE.

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING  SHALL CONTINUE TO PROCESS THIS INFORMATION UNTIL THE CONTRACT BETWEEN US ENDS OR IS TERMINATED BY EITHER PARTY UNDER THE TERMS OF THE CONTRACT.

**INFORMATION WE PROCESS WITH YOUR CONSENT**

THROUGH CERTAIN ACTIONS WHEN OTHERWISE THERE IS NO CONTRACTUAL RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN US, SUCH AS WHEN YOU BROWSE OUR WEBSITE OR ASK US TO PROVIDE YOU MORE INFORMATION ABOUT OUR BUSINESS, INCLUDING OUR PRODUCTS AND SERVICES, YOU PROVIDE YOUR CONSENT TO US TO PROCESS INFORMATION THAT MAY BE PERSONAL INFORMATION.

WHEREVER POSSIBLE, WE AIM TO OBTAIN YOUR EXPLICIT CONSENT TO PROCESS THIS INFORMATION, FOR EXAMPLE, BY ASKING YOU TO AGREE TO OUR USE OF COOKIES.

SOMETIMES YOU MIGHT GIVE YOUR CONSENT IMPLICITLY, SUCH AS WHEN YOU SEND US A MESSAGE BY E-MAIL TO WHICH YOU WOULD REASONABLY EXPECT US TO REPLY.

EXCEPT WHERE YOU HAVE CONSENTED TO OUR USE OF YOUR INFORMATION FOR A SPECIFIC PURPOSE, WE DO NOT USE YOUR INFORMATION IN ANY WAY THAT WOULD IDENTIFY YOU PERSONALLY. WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING **RCE** MAY AGGREGATE IT IN A GENERAL WAY AND USE IT TO PROVIDE CLASS INFORMATION, FOR EXAMPLE TO MONITOR THE PERFORMANCE OF A PARTICULAR PAGE ON OUR WEBSITE.

IF YOU HAVE GIVEN US EXPLICIT PERMISSION TO DO SO, WE MAY FROM TIME TO TIME PASS YOUR NAME AND CONTACT INFORMATION TO SELECTED ASSOCIATES WHOM WE CONSIDER MAY PROVIDE SERVICES OR PRODUCTS YOU WOULD FIND USEFUL.

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING CONTINUES TO PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION ON THIS BASIS UNTIL YOU WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT OR IT CAN BE REASONABLY ASSUMED THAT YOUR CONSENT NO LONGER EXISTS.

YOU MAY WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT AT ANY TIME BY INSTRUCTING US [[HTTPS://WILDHORSEPM.COM/CONTACT](http://wildhorsepm.com/contact)]. HOWEVER, IF YOU DO SO, YOU MAY NOT BE ABLE TO USE OUR WEBSITE OR OUR SERVICES FURTHER.

**INFORMATION WE PROCESS FOR THE PURPOSES OF LEGITIMATE INTERESTS**

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING MAY PROCESS INFORMATION ON THE BASIS THERE IS A LEGITIMATE INTEREST, EITHER TO YOU OR TO US, OF DOING SO.

WHERE WE PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION ON THIS BASIS, WE DO AFTER HAVING GIVEN CAREFUL CONSIDERATION TO:

  * WHETHER THE SAME OBJECTIVE COULD BE ACHIEVED THROUGH OTHER MEANS
  * WHETHER PROCESSING (OR NOT PROCESSING) MIGHT CAUSE YOU HARM
  * WHETHER YOU WOULD EXPECT US TO PROCESS YOUR DATA, AND WHETHER YOU WOULD, IN THE ROUND, CONSIDER IT REASONABLE TO DO SO

FOR EXAMPLE, WE MAY PROCESS YOUR DATA ON THIS BASIS FOR THE PURPOSES OF:

  * RECORD-KEEPING FOR THE PROPER AND NECESSARY ADMINISTRATION OF OUR [ORGANIZATIONAL OR BUSINESS]
  * RESPONDING TO UNSOLICITED COMMUNICATION FROM YOU TO WHICH WE BELIEVE YOU WOULD EXPECT A RESPONSE
  * PROTECTING AND ASSERTING THE LEGAL RIGHTS OF ANY PARTY
  * INSURING AGAINST OR OBTAINING PROFESSIONAL ADVICE THAT IS REQUIRED TO MANAGE [ORGANIZATIONAL OR BUSINESS] RISK
  * PROTECTING YOUR INTERESTS WHERE WE BELIEVE WE HAVE A DUTY TO DO SO

**INFORMATION WE PROCESS BECAUSE WE HAVE A LEGAL OBLIGATION UNDER GDPR COMPLIANCE**

WILDHORSE PERFORMANCE MARKETING IS SUBJECT TO THE LAW LIKE EVERYONE ELSE. SOMETIMES, WE MUST PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION IN ORDER TO COMPLY WITH A STATUTORY OBLIGATION.

FOR EXAMPLE, WE MAY BE REQUIRED TO GIVE INFORMATION TO LEGAL AUTHORITIES IF THEY SO REQUEST OR IF THEY HAVE THE PROPER AUTHORIZATION SUCH AS A SEARCH WARRANT OR COURT ORDER.

THIS MAY INCLUDE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.

**SPECIFIC USES OF INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE TO US**

**SECTION 6 – AGE OF CONSENT**

BY USING THIS SITE, YOU REPRESENT THAT YOU ARE AT LEAST THE AGE OF MAJORITY IN YOUR STATE OR PROVINCE OF RESIDENCE, OR THAT YOU ARE THE AGE OF MAJORITY IN YOUR STATE OR PROVINCE OF RESIDENCE AND YOU HAVE GIVEN US YOUR CONSENT TO ALLOW ANY OF YOUR MINOR DEPENDENTS TO USE THIS SITE.

**COOKIES**

WE MAY COLLECT INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR COMPUTER, INCLUDING YOUR IP ADDRESS, OPERATING SYSTEM AND BROWSER TYPE, FOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION AND IN ORDER TO CREATE REPORTS. THIS IS STATISTICAL DATA ABOUT OUR USERS’ BROWSING ACTIONS AND PATTERNS, AND DOES NOT IDENTIFY ANY INDIVIDUAL.

**SECTION 7 – CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

WE RESERVE THE RIGHT TO MODIFY THIS PRIVACY POLICY AT ANY TIME, SO PLEASE REVIEW IT FREQUENTLY. CHANGES AND CLARIFICATIONS WILL TAKE EFFECT IMMEDIATELY UPON THEIR POSTING ON THE WEBSITE. IF WE MAKE MATERIAL CHANGES TO THIS POLICY, WE WILL NOTIFY YOU HERE THAT IT HAS BEEN UPDATED, SO THAT YOU ARE AWARE OF WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT, HOW WE USE IT, AND UNDER WHAT CIRCUMSTANCES, IF ANY, WE USE AND/OR DISCLOSE IT.

IF OUR STORE IS ACQUIRED OR MERGED WITH ANOTHER COMPANY, YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE TRANSFERRED TO THE NEW OWNERS SO THAT WE MAY CONTINUE TO SELL PRODUCTS TO YOU.

**QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION**

IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO: ACCESS, CORRECT, AMEND OR DELETE ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION WE HAVE ABOUT YOU, REGISTER A COMPLAINT, OR SIMPLY WANT MORE INFORMATION CONTACT OUR PRIVACY COMPLIANCE OFFICER BY USING OUR CONTACT FORM.
